firstinarchitecture.co.uk 2018-05-19

# Cookies and Privacy Policy – First In Architecture

## Introduction

1.1 We are committed to safeguarding the privacy of First In Architecture.  
1.2 This policy applies where we are acting as a data controller with respect to the personal data of First In Architecture visitors and service users; in other words, where we determine the purposes and means of the processing of that personal data.  
1.3 We will ask you to consent to our use of cookies in accordance with the terms of this policy when you first visit our website.  
1.4 This Privacy Policy describes how your personal information is collected, used, and shared when you visit or make a purchase from [first-in-architecture.myshopify.com](http://www.first-in-architecture.myshopify.com/) & [www.firstinarchitecture.co.uk](http://www.firstinarchitecture.co.uk/) (the “Site”).

## Credit

2.1 This document was created using a template from SEQ Legal ([https://seqlegal.com](https://seqlegal.com/)).

## How we use your personal data

3.1 We may process data about your use of our website and services (“usage data“). The usage data may include your IP address, geographical location, browser type and version, operating system, referral source, length of visit, page views and website navigation paths, as well as information about the timing, frequency and pattern of your service use. The source of the usage data is our analytics tracking system. This usage data may be processed for the purposes of analysing the use of the website and services. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely monitoring and improving our website and services.  
3.2 We may process information that you post for publication on our website or through our services (“publication data“). The publication data may be processed for the purposes of enabling such publication and administering our website and services. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the proper administration of our website and business  
3.3 We may process information relating to transactions, including purchases of goods and services, that you enter into with us and/or through our website (“transaction data“). The transaction data may include your contact details, and the transaction details. The transaction data may be processed for the purpose of supplying the purchased goods and services and keeping proper records of those transactions. The legal basis for this processing is the performance of a contract between you and us and/or taking steps, at your request, to enter into such a contract and our legitimate interests, namely our interest in the proper administration of our website and business.  
3.4 We may process information that you provide to us for the purpose of subscribing to our email notifications and/or newsletters (“notification data“). The notification data may be processed for the purposes of sending you the relevant notifications and/or newsletters. The legal basis for this processing is consent. It is possible to unsubscribe from our newsletter at any time.  
3.5 We may process any of your personal data identified in this policy where necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the protection and assertion of our legal rights, your legal rights and the legal rights of others.

## Retaining and deleting personal data

4.1 Personal data that we process for any purpose or purposes shall not be kept for longer than is necessary for that purpose or those purposes.  
4.2 Notwithstanding the other provisions of this Section, we may retain your personal data where such retention is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person.  
4.3 When you place an order through the Site, we will maintain your Order Information for our records unless and until you ask us to delete this information.

## Amendments

5.1 We may update this policy from time to time by publishing a new version on our website.  
5.2 You should check this page occasionally to ensure you are happy with any changes to this policy.

## Your rights

6.1 You may instruct us to provide you with any personal information we hold about you; provision of such information will be subject to:  
(a) the payment of a fee currently fixed at GBP £10; and  
(b) the supply of appropriate evidence of your identity for this purpose, we will usually accept a photocopy of your passport certified by a solicitor or bank plus an original copy of a utility bill showing your current address.  
6.2 We may withhold personal information that you request to the extent permitted by law.  
6.3 You may instruct us at any time not to process your personal information for marketing purposes.  
6.4 In practice, you will usually either expressly agree in advance to our use of your personal information for marketing purposes, or we will provide you with an opportunity to opt out of the use of your personal information for marketing purposes.

## About cookies

7.1 A cookie is a file containing an identifier (a string of letters and numbers) that is sent by a web server to a web browser and is stored by the browser. The identifier is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server.  
7.2 Cookies may be either “persistent” cookies or “session” cookies: a persistent cookie will be stored by a web browser and will remain valid until its set expiry date, unless deleted by the user before the expiry date; a session cookie, on the other hand, will expire at the end of the user session, when the web browser is closed.  
7.3 Cookies do not typically contain any information that personally identifies a user, but personal information that we store about you may be linked to the information stored in and obtained from cookies.

## Cookies that we use

8.1 We use cookies to analyse web data and to improve our website to our readers needs. Cookies help us provide a better website to you by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which pages you do not.

## Cookies used by our service providers

9.1 Our service providers use cookies and those cookies may be stored on your computer when you visit our website.  
9.2 We use Google Analytics to analyse the use of our website. Google Analytics gathers information about website use by means of cookies. The information gathered relating to our website is used to create reports about the use of our website. Google’s privacy policy is available at: <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>.  
9.3 We publish Google AdSense advertisements on our website. To determine your interests, Google will track your behaviour on our website and on other websites across the web using cookies. This behaviour tracking allows Google to tailor the advertisements that you see on other websites to reflect your interests. You can view, delete or add interest categories associated with your browser by visiting: [https://adssettings.google.com](https://adssettings.google.com/). You can also opt out of the AdSense partner network cookie using those settings or using the Network Advertising Initiative’s multi-cookie opt-out mechanism at: [http://optout.networkadvertising.org](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/). However, these opt-out mechanisms themselves use cookies, and if you clear the cookies from your browser your opt-out will not be maintained. To ensure that an opt-out is maintained in respect of a particular browser, you may wish to consider using the Google browser plug-ins available at: <https://support.google.com/ads/answer/7395996>.

## Managing cookies

10.1 Most browsers allow you to refuse to accept cookies and to delete cookies. The methods for doing so vary from browser to browser, and from version to version. You can however obtain up-to-date information about blocking and deleting cookies via these links:  
(a) <https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en> (Chrome);  
(b) <https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences> (Firefox);  
(c) <http://www.opera.com/help/tutorials/security/cookies/> (Opera);  
(d) <https://support.microsoft.com/en-gb/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies> (Internet Explorer);  
(e) <https://support.apple.com/kb/PH21411> (Safari); and  
(f) <https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-10-microsoft-edge-and-privacy> (Edge).  
10.2 Blocking all cookies will have a negative impact upon the usability of many websites.  
10.3 If you block cookies, you will not be able to use all the features on our website.

## Links to Other Websites

11.1 Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have control over that website. Therefore we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement.

## Sharing your data with our Partners

12.1 We work with a number of partners in order to create a streamline customer experience on our site, and to allow us to provide all the services that we have available. For example, we use Shopify to power our online store, and SendOwl to deliver our digital goods. We also use Google Analytics to help us understand how our customers use the Site  
You can view the privacy policy and compliance of our partners by following the links below:  
Aweber <https://www.aweber.com/privacy.htm>  
Shopify <https://www.shopify.com/legal/privacy>  
SendOwl <https://www.sendowl.com/privacy>  
Sellfy <https://sellfy.com/privacy/>  
LeadPages [Leadpages privacy policy](https://www.leadpages.net/privacy?utm_source=drip&utm_medium=email&utm_campaign=GDPR+-+All+Current+Customers&utm_content=Important+Updates%3A+Changes+to+Leadpages%E2%80%99+Privacy+Policy%2C+Terms+of+Service%2C+and+More)  
Google [https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en-GB&gl=uk](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en-GB&gl=uk)  
GeniusLink <https://www.geni.us/privacy>  
Finally, we may also share your Personal Information to comply with applicable laws and regulations, to respond to a subpoena, search warrant or other lawful request for information we receive, or to otherwise protect our rights.

## Changes

We may update this privacy policy from time to time in order to reflect, for example, changes to our practices or for other operational, legal or regulatory reasons.

## Our details

You can contact us:  
(b) using our website contact form; or  
(d) by email, using the email address published on our website from time to time.  
(c) through our social media channels

We will not sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties unless we have your permission or are required by law to do so.
